Be without fear in the face of your enemies.
Safeguard the helpless, and do no wrong
Kingdom of Heaven is a drama, action, adventure film directed by Ridley Scott.
After his wife dies, a blacksmith named Balian is thrust into royalty,
political intrigue and bloody holy wars during the Crusades.
Balian de Ibelin, played by Orlando Bloom.
Sibylla, played by Eva Green.
Tiberias, played by Jeremy Irons.
Hospitaler, played by David Thewlis.
Saladin, played by Ghassan Massoud.
Godfrey de Ibelin, played by Liam Neeson.
Kingdom of Heaven is a 2005 epic historical drama film directed and
produced by Ridley Scott and written by William Monahan.
It features an ensemble cast including Orlando Bloom, Eva Green, Jeremy Irons,
David Thewlis, Brendan Gleeson, Marton Csokas, and Liam Neeson.
The film is a portrayal of the events leading to the Third Crusade, focusing mainly on Balian of Ibelin
who fights to defend the Crusader Kingdom of Jerusalem from the Ayyubid Sultan Saladin.
Filming took place in Ouarzazate, Morocco, and in Spain, at the Loarre Castle (Huesca),
Segovia, Ávila, Palma del Río, and Seville's Casa de Pilatos and Alcázar.
The film was released on 6 May 2005 by 20th Century Fox and
received mixed reviews upon theatrical release.
Reviewers were more positive about the director's
cut released on 23 December 2005.
It grossed $218 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of blacksmith, muslim, crusade, jerusalem, catapult.
The tone is emotional.